Guide to the Stanford University, Board of Trustees, Meeting Records SC1010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Records created prior to 2010, 1885-2009; Series 1
  - Supporting material, 1905-1976, 1998-2009; Subseries 3; 28 Linear Feet (56 boxes)
    - Miller and Lux Inc. - liquidation, 1931 Jul 9 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Petition to include land in Butte Creek Drainage District, Aug. 13, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Gifts, Sept. 17, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Lease of City Hotel, Oct. 8, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Elimination of women students: a proposal by T. T. C. Gregory, Oct. 23, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Documents of the Military Order of the World War entrusted to Hoover War Library; Contrct for endowment campaign cancelled, Dec. 10, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - [no subjects], Jan. 14, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Requirements for advanced degree in Law; Resolution that the Lower Division be reinstated, Feb 11, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Increase in number admitted to Lower Division, Feb 25, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Permission to grant faculty status, without pay, to members of staf or institutions affiliated with Stanford; Requirements for advanced law degree; Bus service contract extended; Amendment to Section 1, Chap. 6 of the By-laws, Mar 10, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Vina property repossessed; Range land in Tehama Co. repossessed, 1932 Apr 14 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - P. G. & E. lease; Rockefeller grant for research in the social sciences, $200,000, 1932 Jun 9 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 1932 Jul 14 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Restrictions governing use of library by persons not connected with the University; Pension plan, 1932 Sep 8 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Plan governing the refunding of tuition in cases of withdrawal of registered students, 1932 Oct 13 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - James Perrin Smith library of Cephalopoda given to University by his wife, 1932 Nov 10 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Herbert Hoover reelected trustee; W. Mayo Newhall reelected trustee, 1932 Dec 15 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 1933 Jan 26 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Union Pacific RR stock; Chicago Rock Island and Pacific RR Co. stock, 1933 Feb 16 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Maul and tie used at the opening of the branch line of the Union Pacific from Las Vegas to Hoover Dam, 1933 Mar 16 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - American Relief Administration appropriation; Ed. D. degree requirements; Sewage plant project in cooperation with City of Palo Alto, 1933 Apr 20 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Limitation of women students dropped, 1933 May 11 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Bacon Building Company; Sale of tehama Co. land to Roy Dearmore, 1933 Jun 8 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Gift of the Cubberleys' estate to the University, 1933 Jul 13 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Annual meeting; Ira S. Lillick reelected Trustee, 1933 Sep 14 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Wilbur recommendation that Stanford not apply for National Industrial Recovery Act funds; Bacon Building Company; University Club request for moratorium on principal payments until 1935; Palo Alto Company lease returned, 1933 Sep 14 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - 1933 Oct 19 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - New dormitory for women proposed, 1933 Nov 9 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Paul Shoup reelected Trustee, 1933 Dec 21 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Revision of Articles of Organization of the faculty; Requirements for admission revised, 1933 Dec 21 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Disposition of David Starr Jordan's ashes; Training of teachers in hygiene and physical education; Reduction in interest asked by California Market Properties Co; T. W. Stanford estate; Boundries of campus proper defined, 1934 Jan 11 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Establishment of Industrial Relations Section recommended; School of Biological Sciences; M. ED. degree established; Proceedings for highway through campus land; Survey for buildings as to their ability to withstand earthquake stresses; Recommendation that earthquake insurance be purchased; Smoking restrictions; Vina land repossessed; Contract for new women's dorm; Board of Athletic Control: gave $5000 to University for a fund raising campaign to help needy students, 1934 Feb 8 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Emergency Relief Administration - funds for the employment of needy students; Pension plan; Administration of University for needy students; Wells Fargo Bank - charges for custody of securities; Esitmates of cost of Lagunita court, 1934 Mar 8 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - California Emergency Relief Administration - funds for students; Commission for Student Aid; Cubberley gift, 1934 Apr 5 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Red Bluff property sale, 1934 May 10 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - California Market Properties Co. request that they be allowed to continue reduced itnterest rate; Alameda property repossession, Jun 14, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Comm. formed to seek funds to increase endowment, 1934 Jul 12 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - [no documents], 1934 Aug 9 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Herzstein Bequest (list of art transfereed from the De Young Museum); Cubberley gift, 1934 Sep 13 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Alumni Jordan Medical Scholarship Fund; Briggs scholarships: Declaration of Trust and correspondence, 1934 Oct 11 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Western Investment Co. lease for gold dredging; Gift from Albert M. Bender, 1934 Nov 8 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Wallace M. Alexander reelected Trustee, 1934 Nov 8 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Pavilion dollar" to be kept in Students' Orgaizations Fund; Bequest from Abraham Rosenberg, 1934 Dec 6 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - [routine financial documents], 1935 Jan 10 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Payment from Ellwood Cubberley, 1935 Feb 14 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Budget for academic year 1935-36, 1935 Mar 14 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Gift from Mrs. Jennie W. Cushing to support a free bed at Lane Hospital, 1935 Apr 11 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Land adjoining Palo Alto property (Ormondale Ranch) offered to University for sale, 1935 May 9 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Francis Price elected trustee, 1935 May 9 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Fund raising program of Stanford Associates; Infantile paralysis research grant, 1935 Jul 18 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Gift of D. S. Jordan memorabilia from Mrs. Jessie K. Jordan (includes list of items), 1935 Sep 20 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Letter re will of Adolph Barkan, deceased; Death of Frank B. Anderson, 1935 Oct 17 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Bequest from Marguerite Gombert; California Market Properties, 1935 Nov 21 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Alumni Association funds; Embarcadero Road underpass, 1935 Dec 19 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Amy L. Hanson - legatee of Jane L. Stanford - will, 1936 Jan 16 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Letter with analysis of Amy Hanson's will; Faculty salaries decreased 10 percent; Stuart L. Rawlings elected trustee; Incorporation of Menlo School proposed; Question of policy of the Stanford Association as to what influence they are to have; Wells Fargo Bank - custodian of securities; Timothy Hopkins - memorial following death of, 1936 Feb 20 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Decree determining and confirming the powers of the trustees with respect to the investment of trust funds; Memorandum opinion on investment policy, 1936 Mar 19 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - [routine matters], 1936 Apr 23 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Memo regarding investment transactions since April 2, 1936 [these appear reqularly from here on and will not be noted each time]; American Legion Subversive Activities Commission: letter condeming Dr. Thomas Addis; Articles of Organization of the Stanford Fund, 1936 Jun 13 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Ellwood and Helen Cubberley Trust Fund, 1936 Jul 16 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - [no documents], 1936 Sep 17 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Frank P. Deering reelected trustee, 1936 Nov 19 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - American Relief Administration liquidation, 1937 Jan 21 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Estimate of budget and income, 1937 Feb 25 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - President's budget for 1937-38, 1937 Mar 25 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Articles of Organization of the School of Medicine; Charles K. Field fund, 1937 Apr 22 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - [no documents], 1937 May 20 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Shell Oil Company's request to establish a fellowship for graduate students, 1937 Jun 17 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Stanford Alumni Assoc. funds: must be kept separately; Report on attempts to purchase property of George A. Lewis near Searsville Lake, 1937 Jul 25 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - John M. Switzer Loan and Scholarship Fund, 1937 Sep 23 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Institute of Industrial Hygiene of the Medical School; University patent policy, 1937 Nov 4 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Forms for gifts, grants, devises and etc., prepared by George Crothers; Investment policy; Audit of University accounts, 1938 Jan 20 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Procudure for estimate of income; David Starr Jordan Memorial Inc; Cubberley re Education Building, 1938 Feb 17 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Insurance for Lagunita Court; Report of Comptroller on Graduate housing; Resolution on patents, 1938 Mar 17 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
    - Investment transactions of the past month; Searsville Lake property; City of Palo Alto - street construction; Comm. on patent policy, 1938 Apr 21 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - University patent policy, 1938 Jun 16 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Estate contingent upon the School of Dentistry of the College of Physicians and Surgeons in S.F becoming a part of Stanford University; Permission asked for Stanford Medical Alumni Assoc. to seek endowment for Stanford Medical School; Gift for Menlo School and Junior College for salaries in the School of Education, 1938 Aug 18 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Joint meeting of committees and full board; Legal expenses in case of estate litigation to be charged against funds received from the estate, 1938 Sep 22 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1938 Oct 20 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Funds for Hoover War Library; Contract with the International Institute for Social History for their collections; Name changed from Hoover War Libray to Hoover Libray on War, Revolution and Peace; Law School endowment, 1938 Nov 17 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Amend statement of University patent policy; Stanford Union dining hall increased; Suggestions for meeting budget requirements, 1939 Jan 19 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Proposal for meeting budget requirements, 1939 Feb 23 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Revised pension projection, 1939 Mar 23 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - 1939 Apr 20 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Comm. appointed to find a president to succeed Dr. Wilbur; Dr. Wilbur asked to reamin another year to officiate during the 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1939 May 18 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - 1939 Jun 15 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - 1939 Jul 20 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - 1939 Sep 21 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Frank F. Walker elected trustee, 1939 Oct 19 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 50th Anniversary Celebration - organization, plans and funding, 1939 Nov 16 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Cubberley gift; Letter from J. D. Grant stating that Gov. Stanford had not wanted a majority of the members of the board to be Stanford graduates as they would tend to interfere with the activities of the president; Donald B. Tresidder elected trustee, 1939 Dec 21 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Federal Telegraph Building, Oakland, leaded to J. C. Penny Co; Joseph D. Grant proposed as Honorary Chairman for 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1940 Jan 18 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Proposal to increase tuition fees; Memorandum on budget estimate, 1940 Feb 15 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Federal Telegraph Building, Oakland, improvement; John T. Nourse reelected trustee; Revised pension projection, 1940 Mar 21 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1940 Apr 18 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Marin Co. lands within the drainage basin of Lagunitas Creek, 1940 May 16 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Increased tuition, 1940 May 22 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - 1940 Jun 20 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Leland W. Cutler reelected trustee; M. C. Sloss relected trustee; Notes on the sale of stock and bonds, 1940 Jul 18 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - C. O. G. Miller reelected trustee; Selection of comptroller; Memo re budget for 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1940 Sep 19 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Frank F. Walker named Financial V-Pres; W. P. Fuller, Jr. resigned from Investment Comm., 1940 Oct 17 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - 1940 Nov 28 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Report of the Rules Comm., 1940 Dec 19 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Charles R. Blyth elected trustee, 1941 Jan 16 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Proposed library fee, 1941 Feb 20 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Financial documents only, 1941 Mar 20 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Detailed distribution of the President's Budget for 1941-42, 1941 Apr 17 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - [no documents], 1941 May 15 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Commmencement Program and Gifts Received, 1941 Jun 18 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Wilbur to be acting president from Jan. 1942 to Jan. 1943; made chancellor Jan. 1942; Blyth, Lillick and Roth named to Special Account Committee; Clarification of gift list - Stanford East Bay Women's Club, 1941 Jul 22 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Univ. Expandsion Comm. names; Supplementary report on the physical condition of the Med School and hospitals - re moving the hospital to Stanford, 1941 Sep 18 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Cubberley gift; Clelia D. Mosher estate, 1941 Oct 16 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Hoover library - trust fund; Helen Cubberley gift; Required physical examinations for faculty; group health plan; Proposal for a Network Calculating Board at Stanford, 1941 Nov 27 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Seven documents, among them the Founding Grant, the Organizaton of the Board of Trustees, 1909, the last wills of Ellwood and Helen Cubberley, taken from Wells Fargo and placed in the vault of the Hoover Library; Stanford Univ. Civilian Defense Council, 1941 Dec 18 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Resolutions adopted on college and Univ. War Problems by a conference of Western Colleges and Universities, 1942 Jan 15 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Futures - T.S.L. Herbert Hoover, 1942 Feb 26 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Estimate of income for fiscal year 1942-43, 1942 Mar 19 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Helen Cubberley - gift of their home to be used as a house for graduate women, 1942 Apr 23 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Budget and other financial documents, 1942 Apr 23 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Organization of the School of Humanities, 1942 May 21 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Commencement Program and Gifts Received, 1942 Jun 18 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Estate of Mary K. Hopkins, 1942 Jul 16 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - George A. Ditz elected trustee; Mrs. Roger Goodan elected trustee; first woman trustee; Rules governing membership on Board of Trustees, 1942 Aug 20 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Amendments to the By-laws and Rules of Order of the Board proposed, 1942 Sep 17 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - John F. Neylan - American History Confernce and the Institute of American History: re the financing of both; Amendments to the By-laws of the Board, 1942 Oct 22 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Report on selection of a president for Stanford: by Don Tresidder, 1942 Nov 25 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Herbert Hoover reelected trustee; Memo to Dr. Wilbur regarding Navy negotiations for training of Navy personnel at Stanford, 1942 Dec 17 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Draft of minutes of meeting at which Tresidder was elected president; Don Tresidder: statement as to the office of the presidency, and the conditions under which he would be able to take the office, 1943 Jan 21 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1943 Feb 25 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Proposed school of military government at S.U., 1943 Mar 18 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1943 Apr 15 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1943 May 20 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - 1943 Jun 17 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Unit Operations Laboratories - cost analysis, 1943 Jul 15 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1943 Aug 19 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - The Knoll leased for WAC trainees; Salaries for house staff at S. F. Hospital; Contrct with the War Dept; Federal Telephone and Radio Laboratories - budget; Survey of Medical School and S. F. Hospital, 1943 Oct 5 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Civil Affairs Specialists Training Program; Tranining Unit Contract: War Dept., for AST AND STAR programs, 1943 Nov 18 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Resolution on death of Lou Henry Hoover, 1944 Jan 20 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Report of Comm on Academic Affairs (ASTP), 1944 Feb 24 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Report upon a Gift Procurement Program for Stanford University, 1944 Mar 16 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Report...to Consider the Students' Petitions Respecting Sororoities at Stanford, 1944 Apr 20 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Academic Affairs Committee minutes; President's Budget 1944-45, 1944 May 18 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Acceptance letters from George Morell and Herman Phleger; Memo re negotiating the concluding steps in the sorority matter, 1944 Jun 16 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1944 Sep 21 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - The Composition of Boards of Trustees [study of college and university boards]; The Organization and Activities of Boards whnich Control Institutions of Higher Learning, abstract of thesis by William A. Ashbrook, 1930, 1944 Oct 19 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Memo on operating statement by Frank F. Walker; Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1944 Nov 16 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence re resolution for Harry Chandler; Resignation of John T. Nourse; Gift from Mary B. Alexander (Mrs. Wallace M. Alexander), 1944 Dec 21 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Resolution of thanks to Mrs. Wallace Alexander; Audit report; Estimate of income, 1945 Jan 18 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Pres. Tresidder's review of the 18 months of his administration (1 page summary); Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1945 Feb 15 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Suggested changes to by-laws; Budget, 1945 Mar 15 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Graphs of medical school expenses; Memorandum on acquisition of 9 former sorority houses, 1945 Apr 19 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1945 May 17 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Comparison Between Audited Budget and Actual Operations for the Fiscal Year 1944-1945; Relationship between the President and the Advisory Board; Digest of President's Budget and detailed departmental distribution; Acceptance letter from John Cushing, 1945 Jun 21 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Chart on student instructor ratios and instructional costs per student for selected universities, 1908 and 1940; Chart on total assets per student for selected universities, 1945 Jul 19 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Audit report on Palo Alto Hospital; Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1945 Sep 20 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - [empty], 1945 Oct 18 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - [empty], 1945 Nov 15 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Resignation letter from Frank F. Walker; Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus, 1945 Dec 13 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Estimated income reports, 1946 Jan 17 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Legal documents re War Dept. training program on campus; Acceptance letter from Seeley G. Mudd, 1946 Feb 21 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - National Housing Agency Federal Public Housing Authority Contract with Local Body to Provide Temporary Housing [blank], 1946 Mar 21 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Budget estimate revisions, 1946 Apr 18 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Hospital salary proposed increases; Letter of appreciation to George E. Crothers, 1946 May 16 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Check signing authorizations, 1946 Jun 20 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - [empty], 1946 Jul 18 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Revised Budget for 1947-147; Memorial statement on Paul Shoup, 1946 Sep 18 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - [no documents], 1946 Oct 17 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Confidential note re faculty member; Budget documents, 1946 Nov 21 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Minutes of special meeting to organize Stanford Research Institute; By-laws of the Stanford Research Institute, 1946 Dec 13 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Gifts received; Minutes (draft form) of first meeting of general members of the Stanford Research Institute, 1946 Dec 19 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Estimated Budget for 1947-48; Corrected set of Rules and By-Laws for Board of Trustees, 1947 Jan 16 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Lewis Mumford's Memorandum on Planning; Budget Estimate 1947-48, 1947 Feb 20 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Resolution passed by Stanford Associates in honor of to President [Tresidder], 1947 Mar 20 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - President's Report for 1945-46; Audit Report for 1945/46 year; Proposal to enlarge Palo Alto Hospital, 1947 Apr 17 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - War Memorial memorandum, 1947 May 15 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Lloyd Dinkelspiel elected to Board, 1947 Jun 19 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Lybrand, Ross Bros. & Montgomery appointed auditors, 1947 Jul 17 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Audit report on Palo Alto Hospital, 1947 Sep 25 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - [no documents], 1947 Oct 16 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - [no documents], 1947 Nov 20 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Resolution on death of Leon Sloss, Jr; May T. Morrison Trust Estate, 1947 Dec 18 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Wage survey - Corporation Yard and Stanford Village; Estimate of Income 1948-49, 1948 Jan 15 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Minutes of Board meeting, 1948 Feb 3 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Detailed budgets for dormitories and dining halls; Budget Estimate 1948-49, 1948 Feb 18 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - 4 page document "Additional Matters", 1948 Mar 18 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - [no documents], 1948 Apr 15 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Quarterly financial statement, May 20, 1948, 1948 May 20 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - DAPER, Statement of Income, 1948 Jun 17 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Financial documents, 1948 Jul 15 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Financial documents, including some from Lane Hospital, 1948 Sep 23 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Report of Special Committee to Develop plans for raising additional funds for School of Medicine, 1948 Oct 21 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Memorandum submitted to the Board by J. E. Wallace Sterling, 17 Nov. 1948 re assuming presidency, 1948 Nov 18 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Minutes, wherein Sterling is appointed President, 1948 Nov 19 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Minutes, wherin Clarence E. Faust is appointed acting president, 1948 Dec 3 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Financial History of Stanford for February 1949 Alumni Review; Stanford Research Institute - financial documents and comments on research program by Ralph Krause, 1948 Dec 16 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Estimate of Income 1949-50, 1949 Jan 20 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Budget Estimate 1949-50 and Quarterly Financial Statement, 1949 Feb 17 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - [no documents], 1949 Mar 17 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Amendment to By-Laws of SRI; Report on Eating Clubs; Quarterly Financial Statement, 1949 Apr 21 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Financial documents; Letter from Mary Curry Tresidder rer settling into home on campus, 1949 May 19 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - [folders not yet reviewed for details], July 21, 1949 - December 20, 1951 (Box 28)
    - Liquor control law; Estimate of Income 1952-53; Land development; Faculty salaries, January 17, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Audit reports for year ended August 31, 1951; Budget Estimate 1952-53, 1952 Feb 21 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Changes to By-laws, 1952 Mar 20 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Estate of Helen Cubberley, 1952 Apr 17 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Financial statement, 1952 May 15 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Statement of income and expenses from Rose Bowl Jan. 1, 1952; Letter re proposed retail center on Lot 1, 1952 Jun 19 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Financial statement, 1952 Jul 17 (Box 29, Folder 7)